Guide to the Richard Pryor Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Richard Pryor collection
1971-1991
JWJ MSS 179
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.84
2 boxes
Pryor, Richard, 1940-2005
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Walter Reuben, Inc. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
The Richard Pryor Collection is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Richard Pryor Collection. James Weldon Johnson Collection in the Yale Collection of American Literature, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
Biographical / Historical
Richard Pryor (1940-2005), American stand-up comedian, social critic, and actor.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains film scripts, promotional photographs taken on film sets, press kits, and a storyboard relating to the acting career of Richard Pryor. The collection spans 1971 to 1991.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Scripts, Photographs, Press Kits, and Storyboard.
Actors -- United States -- Archives; African American actors -- Archives; Comedians -- United States -- Archives; Screenplays -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographic prints; Scripts (Motion pictures) -- United States -- 20th Century; Actors -- United States -- 20th Century; Comedians -- United States -- 20th Century; Pryor, Richard, 1940-2005
- Scripts, 1971-1983
  - The Bingo Long Traveling All-Stars and Motor Kings, 1975 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brewster's Millions, first draft, 1983 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family Dream, first draft, 1979 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Family Dream, final draft, 1979 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Greased Lightning, revised draft, 1979 June 30-September 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes staff and crew list
  - Lady Sings the Blues, final shooting script, 1971 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Some Kind of Hero, revised draft, 1971 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes shooting schedule
  - Uptown Saturday Night, revised final draft, 1973 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Which Way is Up, revised final draft, 1977 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1976-1988
  - The Bingo Long Traveling All-Stars and Motor Kings, seven black and white photographs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Blue Collar, three black and white photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bustin' Loose, eight color photographs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Car Wash, one black and white photograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - California Suite, two black and white photographs, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Comedy Store 15th Year Class Reunion, one black and white photograph, 1988 September 2 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Greased Lightning, one black and white photograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Mack, three color photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Richard Pryor: Here and Now, two color photographs, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Silver Streak, one black and white photograph, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Superman III, two black and white photographs, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Wattstax, one black and white photograph, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Press kits, 1979-1991
  - Another You, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Includes six black and white photographs
  - Critical Condition, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Includes twelve black and white photographs
  - Harlem Nights, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Includes nine black and white photographs
  - Live on the Sunset Strip, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes three black and white photographs and two color posters
  - Richard Pryor: Live in Concert, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Five black and white photographs
  - Some Kind of Hero, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Includes seven black and white photographs
- Storyboard, 1986
  - Jo Jo Dancer, Your Life is Calling, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)